# Ethan J. Reimer

ereimer18@georgefox.edu | (253) 709-0006 | linkedin.com/in/ethan-reimer-0487a9178 | github.com/ereimer18

# **Professional Summary**

Highly motivated computer science major with a focus in cybersecurity. A devoted team member with leadership skills, dedication and experience working with a variety of groups and cultures. Able to diligently perform a wide variety of tasks with key organizational skills and close attention to detail. Curious with a strong desire to learn and take on projects offering new skills.

## **Education**

# George Fox University, Newberg, OR

Expected April 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Cyber Security | GPA: 3.64

**Relevant Coursework:** Data Structures, Digital Logic, Software Engineering, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Security and Digital Forensics, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Analysis of Algorithms, Emerging Mobile Technologies, Database Systems, Data Communications and Networks, Computer Architecture/Assembly Languages, Servant Engineering, Operating Systems, Network Administration, Secure Software, Advanced Security, Structures of Programming Languages, Parallel and Distributed Computing, Web Development, Senior Design

#### **Technical Skills**

- Python
- Java
- C/C++
- C#
- Scala
- HTML
- CSS

- Git
- JUnit Testing
- Docker
- SQL
- PostgreSQL
- Linux
- Virtual Machines

- Command-line
- Penetration Testing
- UML
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Network Protocols
- Multithreading

### **Collegiate Projects**

- Senior Design HoloLens Augmented Reality Development (*current*): in conjunction with Daimler Trucks, my senior-design team is developing an Augmented Reality application for a Microsoft HoloLens using Unity and Microsoft's Multiple Reality Took Kit and the Cortana voice assistant to provide a holographic view of important schematics and notifications.
- Chess: Object-Oriented implementation of a command-line driven chess game.
- Servant Engineering Haptic Feedback Device: a haptic feedback device to aid visually impaired students in understanding a graphical image. My particular focus was in developing a color tracking program utilizing computer vision.
- Capitol Breach Incident Response Plan: researched and formulated an emergency cybersecurity incident response plan following the January 6<sup>th</sup>, 2021 breach of the U.S. Capitol building.
- **Magic Mirror IoT Device:** configured and built a "magic mirror" smart device, consisting of a pi-driven monitor behind a two-way mirror that displayed modules such as the weather and notifications.
- **Movie Database:** parsed old HTML and XML files of movies, actors, studios, directors and more and created a PostgreSQL movie database containing the valid data.
- **Networking RFP:** drafted a bid in response to a hypothetical business Request for Proposal in my Data Communications and Networking course. Researched networking equipment and protocols necessary and put together a plan to restore a company to working order and improve network setup.

#### **Contests**

- National Cyber League
  - o Spring 2021
  - o Fall 2021

### **Work Experience**

## Barista, Chapters Books and Coffee, Newberg, OR

Aug 2021-present

- Daily provide excellent and helpful customer service.
- Constantly learning new techniques to improve skill, efficiency, and quality.
- Maintenance and organization of the space and inventory

# Dough Roller, Abby's Legendary Pizza, Newberg, OR

June 2021-Aug 2021

- Rolled dough in a fast-paced environment with quality and consistency.
- Efficient teamwork allowed for a streamlined process.

### Groundskeeper, LifeWay Church, Federal Way, WA

Dec 2020-Jan 2021

- Assisted staff to prepare for events.
- Installed several new camera systems to improve livestreaming capabilities.
- General maintenance and organization of the church property.

### Retail Associate, Lowes, Federal Way, WA

June 2020-Aug 2020

- Provided considerate and helpful customer service.
- Assisted customers in finding merchandise, answering questions, and loading heavy items.
- Aimed to improve and maintain the organization of my department and the availability of products.

#### Amazon Warehouse Associate, Amazon, Kent, WA

May 2019-July 2019

• Stocked and distributed items as a water-strider working with my team to provide optimal product availability to customers.

#### **Volunteer Experience**

**Bryansk**, **Russia**: served alongside local church leaders and international workers to better reach the needs of the community during the summers of 2016 through 2018. Self-taught basic conversational language skills during and after my time on the field.

**ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest, 2018:** volunteered to help run the Oregon ACM ICPC hosted by George Fox University.

#### **Leadership Experience**

Principal Cellist, Stadium High School Chamber Orchestra

2017-2018

Co-Principal Cellist, George Fox University Symphony

2018-2019

#### **Personal Interests**

Rock Climbing

Languages

Skiing

Espresso brewing

Baking

Cello

Backpacking

Disc golf

Guitar